

YUVCIC JAVA BACKEND / MICROSERVICES DEVELOPER

PROFILE

Java developer with 6 years of experience having Strong knowledge on J2EE, Spring MVC, Spring boot, Hibernate to build Rest API's and having experience in working with databases in writing queries and stored procedures. Also crave to learn new technologies and have a working understanding of frontend frameworks such as Angular.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Birth date

22/03/1995

Nationality

Indian

CONTACT

yuvaraj2295@gmail.com

+91-8608275333

in yuvaraj-g

🗻 yuvaaraaja

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

TEK SYSTEMS 2021 - Present

Worked on adding a new feature in a microservice based on Spring Boot that is used for Address validation purposes.

Supporting and maintaining JRA (Java Referenced Architecture) framework, which used by applications that run on WAS servers all over State Farm network. This framework provides all the boilerplate functionalities that is needed for any enterprise application to run.

Technology Analyst

INFOSYS 2020 - 2021

Designed and developed a set of 4 microservices using Spring Boot and Apache Camel as a replacement of legacy Integration platform (webMethods) and released it into production in cloud (AWS) thereby increasing the performance of the web service and implemented new features requested by the client (Bpost).

Worked in an Agile team on user stories for adding new features in an full stack warehouse management application that uses Angular for front end and Spring Boot for backend.

Associate

COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS

2016 - 2020

Worked as a developer and support analyst in IMES (Integrated Manufacturing Execution System) – A Java enterprise application built using Servlet framework used for core manufacturing process across 3M factories in US.

Worked as a developer to add new functionalities in IMES API - A Java REST API built using Spring MVC and Hibernate which enables external applications to connect, access and process information from a centralized database dedicated for manufacturing process.

EDUCATION

B. Tech(Information Technology)

SRI RAMAKRISHNA ENGINEERING COLLEGE

2012 - 2016

Higher Secondary Education (12th - Computer Science)

VIDYAAVIKAS MATRIC HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL

2010 - 2012

• Secondary School Leaving Certificate (10th)

JAYCEE HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL

2009 - 2010

SKILLS

100% Ja

Java 8, JDBC, Junit

50%

Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Spring data

75%

PostgreSQL, MySQL, Hibernate

25%

JavaScript, Angular



Maven, Docker, Jenkins, Git, ActiveMQ



AWS (ECS, Lambda functions)



Linux Shell Scripting, Python